Max Nachlinger / max.nachlinger@gmail.com / https://github.com/maxnachlinger

About me:

I'm a full-stack developer with over ten years of experience building applications. Over the past 4 years I've been doing a lot of NodeJS and front-end JS work as well. I also have experience with various databases, services, and a few other languages and platforms. Not only am I passionate about clean, testable code, but I love teaching, learning, and building cool things alongside smart folks.

Languages / platforms:

- NodeJS
- Front-end JS via React/Redux
- RabbitMQ
- SQL language / MySQL (and Amazon RDS) / Postgres / SQL Server
- MongoDB
- Redis / Amazon Elasticache / Memcached
- Various AWS services
- C#

Other skills:

- TDD
- Agile / SCRUM Experience
- Build / CI Experience (Grunt, Gulp, Jenkins, Travis, CircleCI)
- Open-source contributor
- Management of small development teams / mentoring

Experience:

Developer - nearForm Ltd. - 4/2016 - present

 Worked on an application allowing users to play-test game releases for a major video game company. This project involved NodeJS on the server, React and socket.io on the website, and a C# desktop client as well.

Consultant - Universal Mind, Inc. / Max Nachlinger, LLC. - 7/2015 - 3/2016

- Built out a REST API powering a few human genome apps using NodeJS
- Created a simple auth micro service.
- Worked on a distributed system to import and transform human genome data.

Software Developer - NeonMob, Inc. - 2/2015 - 6/2015

 Maintained neonmob.com, an AngularJS / Python (Django) and NodeJS app allowing the trading and purchase of digital artwork. Built out a REST API using NodeJS for neonmob.com

Developer - Mindflash Technologies, Inc. - 3/2012 - 2/2015

- Built out several large REST APIs using NodeJS.
- Created a distributed system to convert various documents and presentations to web-viewable formats (including videos) via NodeJS, the AWS SDK, RabbitMQ, and C#.

- Engaged in frequent code reviews, mentoring, and pair programming.
- Added localization to all NodeJS parts of our application.

Consultant - Universal Mind, Inc. - 7/2011 - 3/2012

- Ported the main customer-service application (used in retail stores and call centers) for a large telecommunications company from AIR to the browser / flash-player.
- Developed several enhancements to the above application as well.

Developer - Mindflash Technologies, Inc. - 12/2009 - 7/2011

- Developed an online learning management system via Adobe Flex, C#, NHibernate, and SQL Server.
- Built various windows services to backup AWS images, monitor error logs, and perform other infrastructure tasks.
- Mentored junior developers and conducted code-reviews. Developed and documented a set of Flex and C#/midtier best practices.

Senior RIA Engineer - Andromeda Systems, Inc. - 4/2008 - 12/2009

- Developed Rich Internet Applications in Adobe Flex 3, C#, and SQL Server.
- User interface design and prototyping.
- Mentored junior developers and trained staff. Instituted daily builds and code reviews.

Manager of Software Applications - Logix3, LLC. - 9/2003 - 4/2008

Designed and implemented the following applications:

- A BPO based workflow services suite which became the core corporate offering to large clients.
- A media-asset management solution allowing efficient storage, categorization, and retrieval of marketing materials.
- A product information management and quality assurance application allowing vendor / supplier verification of key enterprise data points such as FDA / USDA / HAZMAT / Kosher information.
- An online marketing material design and generation application.

Lead Developer - EscapeArtist.com, Inc. S.A. - 11/2002 - 9/2003

• Developed applications for an international user-base.

Developer - Florida State University School of Information Studies - 12/2001 - 11/2002

• Developed various applications for students and faculty.

Education:

Master of Science - Information Science - The Florida State University Bachelor of Arts - Philosophy - The University of Miami